Subtitles brought to you by the Figaro Cuisine Squad
Hello everyone, good evening
Today I'm live streaming Samantha
I don't know if you guys still remember
I did a live stream of XiaoNiu before
So today I'll bring you guys a self-designed live stream
So today's live stream is mainly about
How to make this self-designed hair, shoes
And also a self-designed zipper and buckle
First of all, let's talk about how to make self-designed hair
For self-designed hair, first of all
We need to open our virtual model in Clou
If you want to do male model, then open male model
If you want to do female model, then open female model
After opening it, we need to
Put this virtual model
Remove the hair of the model
And also remove the shoes of the model
Remove the entire model of the virtual model
And then take this out
On the basis of this virtual model model
To make this shoe and our hair
Then our shoes
Because there are flat shoes and high heels shoes
So here, the foot posture
Is also necessary to adjust
So first of all
Let's make a flat shoe
Then let's go to the file
Make it out
Let's choose the format of FBX
Then here
Let's open a file path
Keep it here
And then the username
Everyone pay attention
The username must be the English size
And the lower line
Don't have Chinese
OK
So this is a flat shoe
A FBX of a flat shoe
Then save it
Then when you open this window
Remember to click on this one
Including virtual model
Then click OK
Otherwise the virtual model
Is not going to be taken out
Then click OK
Put our one virtual model
The virtual model of flat shoes is taken out
Then we are on the ankle
Not on the ankle
On the model
Right click
Adjust the heel
Turn it up
Is the posture of our high heels shoes
Then we choose the file again
Select FBX
We are here
We are also
Give it out
So I changed the name to up
Click save
Then it is the same
To hook up
Including our virtual model
Then click confirm
Then put our
These two FBX
It's all out
After that
Next
We are going to come to
Other 3D software
Put his hair
Put his shoes on
Then here
This 3D software
You can be 3D Max
Can Maya
C4D
And so on
I am more used to using Blender
So I will use this Blender
To explain
Then come to this Blender
First of all
The first one
Is to change its unit
Because of our
In the cloud
Our unit is in red
In order to avoid
This kind of
Between the software
Out of the way
One by one
In order to avoid
This kind of software
Out of the way
One size
Compatibility problem
So here
It's best
Two software units
All in one
Then here
A unit of Blender
From the original
Mi
Change to mm
Then after the modification
We are next
Select the file
Insert
FBX
Then we
Just
Under the
That
Now
Find our
Virtual model
Then
We insert
One of the virtual models
Then
Insert
Then we
We can
On this
Virtual model
On the basis
Do hair
And shoes
One addition
Because of the time
I'm here
It's for everyone
Take a look
Directly added
One file
Sorry
I slipped
Click open
Then
Added
Hair
You can see
A complete
Self-defined hair model
It's like this
It's a little ugly
I'll tell you later
Why
We can see
This hair
It looks like
There is a
The film is wrapped
Then
We put this film
Hide it
After that
You can see
Our
Short hair
That is
When we communicate
Used
This one
Short hair
Then
This
Short hair
After doing
Is all of us
One
That
Self-defined
Object
Is our
Hair
After that
We first
Is to check
The direction of the grid
That is
All of the directions
Must face the outside
Can't appear
The situation of the opposite side
Then
In the
We can go to
Check its effect
Red
Is the opposite
Then
Blue
Is the front
Then
Like this
Face the outside
Is normal
If you
Have some grid
Need to meet
This
Like this
This red grid
Face the outside
Then
This one
After
OK
Then
After handling
This
Hair
Model
After that
What's next
Just like
I just said
To give him
Increase
A layer of the outer package grid
Then
This layer of grid
Is called
When
The grid
Then
This grid
Is actually
To prevent
This
Clip
With
Our hair
这个头发模型在制作的过程当中,为了做出比较好的形状,可能会有一些比较复杂的一些网格结构,那么板片穿进去的话就会容易不稳定,所以就要增加一层这样的一个 downy mesh, ok,那么现在的话我们就是在这个3D模型做好之后呢,我们现在要讲一下就是downy mesh的一个材质,
那因为正常的一个头发,像我这一边的一个头发,正常做好之后导入到close里面的时候呢,是这个样子的,就是我们可以看到它外面我们是看不见它有一层包裹的网格的,但实际上呢我们在这个建模的时候呢,是会有这样的一层网格,那么这一层网格的话呢,我们为了让它在close当中不被看见,所以我们要对它的材质进行一个设定,
那么首先我们来到我们的这个材质槽这一边,然后给它去增加一个新的材质,并指定给我们的downy mesh,然后这边的命名的话呢,我们也进行一下修改,
然后我们把这个downy mesh的一个材质,把它的一个基础色,那么有一些软件是color map,有些是default map,但是都是一样,
用来指定颜色,
的一个贴图,那么基础色这一边点击一下,我们来使用这一个图像纹理,然后点击图像纹理,这边点击打开啊,然后我们可以找到一个,这边的话,我是先提前做好了一个完全透明的一个图片啊,就是导到ps里面呢,就没有像素的,完全是一个灰白格子的一个状态,然后点击打开图像,那这样的话呢,它的一个基础色的一个贴图,就是一个全透明的图片,在close里面的时候呢,它才会容易看到一个全透明的图片,然后我们可以找到一个,这边的话,我是先提前做好了一个完全透明的一个图片,就是导到ps里面呢,就没有像素的,完全是一个灰白格子
可以变成这种透明的一个状态的啊,那这样的话,我们这一个头发这一部分啊,就材质这一部分就处理好了,那么处理好之后呢,我们来选中这一个头发的物件,然后呢,我们来到文件导出啊,也是请注意啊,要导出格式为fbx,然后导出了之后呢,这一边的话,大家要非常注意这一个路径的问题啊,因为你们的路径如果没有处理好的话,可能就会
出现这一个文理丢失的问题,那这边的话,我就选择复制的一个方式,然后呢,勾选这个选定的物体,因为我只选中了hair,不然的话,它会把整个avatar都给导出去的,然后接下来呢,物体类型,大家请注意呢,只导出这个网格啊,像我们的相机啊,灯光啊,等等其他的东西呢,都是不导出的啊,就只导出我们的网格,然后我们再点击导出fbx啊,这样的话,我们的这一个
啊,fbx就导出去了,看一下大家有没有一些什么啊,问题啊,呃,怎么样去做头发模型啊,啊,头发模型这个,你们可以在软件里面自己去建模,那也可以呢,啊,在一些线上购物平台当中进行购买啊,有非常多的一个模型素材是可以购买的,那么购买回来之后呢,啊,可以根据我们虚拟模特的头型稍微调整一下,就可以直接用来使用了,
嗯。
OK。
没有下载过Blender,不知道容易不容易安装啊,Blender非常容易安装啊,因为Blender是一个开源的软件,那么就可以免费使用的,你直接啊,呃,百度一下啊,Blender的官网,然后直接下载就可以了。
啊,我们现在用的是Blender哦。
啊,然后我们的这一个fbx的话呢就啊。
倒出来之后接下来我们来打开我们的close
那我现在把我这个头发给删掉
那我们的FBX倒完之后呢
我们要打开我们的close
然后并且呢把我们倒出来的这个FBX呢
在close当中呢打开
确认一下它的一个位置是正确的
尺寸是正确的
那么这个呢主要是为了避免大家在倒入倒出的时候
可能一些轴的方向啊
或者一些单位的问题啊
导致这一个尺寸或者是位置不对
那么大家可以在这里进行进一步的确认
确认没有问题之后呢
我们就可以去做这一个自定义的头发了
那我们来选中虚拟模特
然后自定义头发鞋子
然后在这里呢请注意一下一个非常重要的点
例如说你的头发是要绑定在飞飞上面
那么你就把飞飞打开
如果你是要绑定在蓝膜上面就把蓝膜打开好
就是对
然后呢我们就把这个头发呢
它的这个绑定是绑定在你当前打开的这个虚拟模特上面的
然后
呃
我们把这一个头发鞋子这里
啊
首先内心的话是选择头发
然后呢
把这一个fb
x呢给他去加载进来啊
我们选中刚刚导出的这个fbx
然后呢打开一个缩略图
那么呃缩略图的话就是提前做好的一个缩略图啊
那大家呃也可以在刚刚就是fbx导进来确认位置的时候呢就把这一个缩略图呢随便用快照给做出来了
然后呢选进来之后呢点击生成
点击生成
然后就会弹出窗口
那么我们就保存出来啊
然后给他命名一下
保存成一个头发
点击保存
那么他是需要一点时间进计算
然后看一下你们又说些什么哈
嗯
捏捏啊
捏捏的话目前在crow还不行哦
捏捏你可以像dash out
呃
或者是其他三点软件也可以啊
用雕刻啊
雕刻工具就可以去捏捏了
ok
然后完成之后呢
呃他会有个提示框的
那么我这边我就把它关闭啊
然后他生成出来的hair就是这一个啊
这一个头发
我文件的格式是z a c s
啊
这些好
那么把这个文件给拖进来
那我们就可以看到呢
这个头发啊
就完成了
好那么接下来呢我们来看一下这一个头发好的当年卖是怎么做啊可能也会有人会有疑惑啊呃当年卖是要怎么做那其实这一个呢呃也不是很难啊那我先把我原本的这一个当年卖是呢给删掉啊然后呃在这个物体模式下面啊首先我们先给他去新建一个经纬球
ok
先给他去新建一个球
然后说
稍微
网格数量可以调多一点点没关系的然后把他的尺寸进行一下修改啊
这样有点太小了
嗯
ok
然后呢把它移动到我们的模特的头上啊
我们可以去打开啊
它的一个网格然后呢去来看一下它是否呢完整的把它的一个头发全部包裹进去好
ok
那么全部包裹了之后呢
我们可以切换一下显示方式然后接下来的话呢我们可以用brand里面有个工具叫做添加修改器啊呃然后这一边的话我们来用一个叫做缩果的一个工具啊选中缩果然后呢选中它的目标呢就是我们的care然后它就会以最近的点呢去把这个经纬球包裹在我们的头发模型上面然后它的便宜量呢可以进行一下调节啊让它不再有太大变化啊然后我们可以切换一下显示方式然后接下来的话呢我们可以用brand里面有个工具叫做添加修改器啊然后这一边的话我们来用一个叫做缩果的一个工具选中缩果然后呢选中它的目标呢就是我们的care然后他就会以最近的点呢去把这个经
要不要就是太多的这一种露出来那当然了大家请注意啊便宜量呢也不适宜太大比如说我像五公分那么这样的话它整个downy mesh呢它虽然是把头发给包住了但是它过大然后它就是呃相当于把你整个头发的体积都给长大了因为这一个downy mesh它也是存在这一个冲突计算的如果你们后面在这个头发的基础上去做像hoodie啊这样有帽子的衣服的话那么它这一个头发的基础上去做像hoodie啊这样有帽子的衣服的话那么它这一个头发的基础上去做像hoodie啊这样有帽子的衣服的话那么它这一个头发的基础上去做像hoodie啊这样有帽子的衣服的话那么它这一个
这么不过大的这个当年卖是就会把这一个帽子给撑开那这样他的情况那么这样他的形态就会非常不好看啊就是不是一个贴着头发的一个效果 这么不过大的这个旁边 más就会把这个帽子给撑开那这样他的形态就会非常不好看啊就是不是一个贴着头发的一个效果 so 在这里的话呢便用要要注意一下不要太大稍微有一点点穿出来没关系的话没有关系的我们后面的话还会用其他工具进行一个精修的啊 才会用也要要注意一下不要太大稍微有一点点穿出来没关系的话没关系的啊我们后面的话还会用其他工具进行一个精修的啊 我们用完这个锁呀爆之后能吗可以点击icular decide用 teachingsчно my byaisa
a confirmation of the modifier, and then the next one, its current network grid is actually very
disadvantageous to us. This part of the part that is exposed is a little hidden by it because we will use the carving tool.
This network grid is not suitable for carving, so we have to make a reset network grid for it.
Then we are also here in the modifier. Let's choose this reset network grid.
Then a body size of the reset network grid can be adjusted,
and then the smaller the number, the more dense the network grid it produces,
and then after it is produced, it is such an effect.
It basically covers most of it.
Just a little bit of the small part can be adjusted,
and then we also click on the application to complete this modifier.
Next, we can come to this carving mode,
and then use our carving to process it.
It's like this.
Slowly put it together like this.
Cover it a little bit.
Because of the good time relationship, I didn't finish the whole thing completely,
because it might take a lot of time.
So everyone,
because you don't understand,
maybe you don't know much about the basics of other 3D software.
Then you can just search for some basic tutorials and then follow up.
It's actually very simple.
After you have mastered some basic skills, you can do this hair.
Like me, I'm not a master either.
I'm just a material, but I can do it all.
OK.
Then we can process it like this.
If it's so well processed,
the last thing is to put this downy mesh,
which is this ball and our hair,
into a merger.
Put it together,
and then the next job will be the same as before.
Apply a downy mesh material to it,
and then pour it out.
OK.
Add downy mesh.
Because of this downy mesh,
you can understand that it is like a protective film.
Wrap this hair up,
and then avoid this board and this hair.
When they stick together,
there will be some reasons for the simulation to be unstable.
The simulation is unstable.
OK.
So this is the process of a hair.
So next,
let's talk about the process of a model shoe.
Then I will continue to go back to the blender.
Then I open a blender file that I prepared before.
Then the shoes are the same as we do the hair.
That is, we put this shoe on the model's feet.
At the same time,
we also have to give it a downy mesh like this,
and stick the whole shoe together.
Wrap it up.
This is actually also for doing some relatively long styles.
For example, when it comes to skirts or long pants,
the board does not appear to be unstable with this shoe.
So you can add an extra layer of protective film.
When...
Oh, sorry.
Where is this software downloaded?
In the case of blender,
you can download it directly on the blender's official website.
This is a free software.
You can download it directly and use it.
Oh, I want to do a short hair.
Oh, here I will give you a small point.
Sorry, I just missed a very important point.
That is, when we are doing a customized hairstyle for this virtual model,
please pay attention.
For this hairstyle,
try to do short hair.
Short hair or behind.
It can be a bun hair.
It can also be.
That is, try not to overdo your hair.
Because our hair also has conflicts.
If your hair is over the shoulder,
then it will be very inconvenient for you to make clothes.
Then maybe you can only do the lower body or the chest.
Or this is a one-piece shoulder.
Otherwise, his hair will fight with the board.
Then you will not be able to do this kind of thing like the collar.
Well, if you really want to do a very beautiful character.
Then I want to make him a long hair.
Then what to do?
Then you just make the clothes first.
And then make his posture better.
Then after the whole one is done,
the whole one is transferred to the other 3D software.
Then make his long hair.
Then this one will involve the long hair and the model's some posture.
And one of the positions of his clothes.
Then after the adjustment,
then the whole one can be transferred to the cloud to show off.
So long hair is a production like this.
OK, then we come back.
Back to the shoes.
The shoes on this side.
We are here.
In addition to doing a downing mesh like ours just now.
There is also a very important point.
It is for high heel shoes.
In the case of high heel shoes,
its heel must be separated into a material.
That is to say, the whole heel part.
It is an application of a heel material.
A material of the heel.
Then this shoe heel material is to be placed at the bottom of all materials.
Then this is a software identification principle.
So when you are doing this self-defined high heel shoe,
you must pay attention to this point very much.
Otherwise, it will be self-defined failure.
Then here.
Maybe everyone will have a situation.
That is to say, when you are doing this shoe,
it may be in the cloud.
I want my shoes.
I can change a color.
Then my one diamond.
You can also separate its material settings.
And this one under the diamond.
You can also give it a separate material setting.
If you want to make such a shoe.
Then you are in this software.
Other software is to set its material.
So like this now.
My diamond.
Diamond surface.
Is to use a material.
Then.
The bottom.
This is the case.
It's another material to use.
Sorry.
Just now it's the shortcut.
Hit the wrong one.
OK.
And it's the bottom.
The diamond side is a material.
The bottom is a material.
Then the shoes are materials.
So after separating the different materials.
In this cloud.
You can also target different materials.
不同部位的一个颜色以及材质的一个设定啊
那这样的话呢我们把整一个鞋子啊全部做好
然后做好之后呢我们一样呢是要把这个鞋子进行一个倒出
那么倒出的时候呢我们请注意啊
我们的鞋子啊在倒出之前一定要把它的网格呢给
分开两个物体就是左鞋和右鞋
那么左鞋的话呢一定要命名为 Shoes Left
Shoes Left非常重要啊
它的物体名称一定要命名为 Shoes Left
然后呢右鞋的话就是 Shoes Right
就是一定是这样的
不分大小写但是一定是要这样的一个命名
然后命名完之后呢
我们可以选中这两个鞋子啊
选中两个物体然后选中文件倒出
然后呢也是一样格式为倒出 FBX啊
然后FBX然后这边的话也是路径
是复制然后选定的物体是导出网格
那这一个的话就是和我们的头发是一样的
然后就是给它导出出去
OK看一下大家说什么啊
呃高筒靴可以做吗
高筒靴也是可以做的
我就是和这个鞋子是完全一样的啊
就是一样的做法
就是如果你的高筒靴是高跟的话呢
那么也是一样在鞋跟的网格一定要给它应用一个Q的材质
并且放置在所有材质的最后方啊
并且呢这个物体的名称也是 shoes left shoes white
所有的鞋子都是这样的一个命名规则
然后呢靴子也是可以做的啊
嗯
呃材质的设置可以在brand里面设置吗
呃材质的设置brand里面的材质设置和code的材质设置是不会互通的
因为这两个软件的一个材质的基层数据是不一样的
但是呢贴图是互通的
所以你像那个
呃那个就是code里面的纹理也就是brand里面的
呃基础色的那个贴图啊是可以互通的
发现图也是可以互通的啊
现在贴图都是可以互通但是材质设定的话呢是不互通的
下载brand软件有链接吗
哦这一个的话你直接在百度一下就可以了
就可以找到brand的官网
然后直接去到他download的页面去下载就可以了
好
然后我们这一个鞋子就导出出去了
那么和我们做这一个头发是一样的啊鞋子呢要把它导入到code当中啊就fbx导到code当中
去来确认一下呢它的位置是没有问题的啊
像这样位置没有问题就可以给它去做自定义了
好那么确认之后呢把鞋子呢给它删除啊
删除之后
然后
像现在我们的鞋子是高跟鞋嘛对吧
所以我们的虚拟模特的姿势呢也是要高跟鞋的一个姿势啊
然后我们来选中虚拟模特自定义头发鞋子
然后这边的话选择鞋子
然后选择高跟鞋
然后我们再来选中我们的一个鞋子的fbx啊
然后这边缩略图呢也给它去添加一下
然后点击生成啊
然后把它给保存一下
嗯
That's it.
Okay, that's a normal shoe.
Of course, you don't have to worry about
whether you will use it like this later.
You don't need to.
It's just that it's the first time we've done it like this.
It's just that we just did it
because its foot is in the position of the foot,
so it needs to be like this.
If we were to open a virtual model,
it was originally a default shoe,
and then when you put the high heel shoe that you finished doing in,
it's a normal display.
It won't be like this,
the foot will be lifted up like this.
Okay, so this is the production of our shoes.
And then,
next, we're going to enter our default component.
Then we'll put a costume on this side first.
It's convenient for us to talk about this default zipper.
Let's open it up in the front.
Then I'll tell you about the default zipper later.
There are also
a lot of things that you can do with the default zipper.
Let's go to the Blender.
Then next,
let's open a zipper file.
This is an OBJ of a zipper that was made in advance.
So after opening it,
first of all,
let's give you a description.
It's a zipper in Chlo.
The zipper.
There are four types of zipper.
Then we have several types of zipper.
It's a zipper with a zipper on the top and a zipper on the bottom.
There are a total of four types of zipper.
Then I will pay attention to explain to you.
So first of all,
it's a zipper with a zipper on the top and a zipper on the bottom.
In fact,
if you make this zipper zipper,
I think it's much easier than hair.
It's much easier than hair shoes.
Because the zipper,
as long as you put it in the right place,
and then the size is correct,
there's no problem.
So first of all,
it's one of its positions.
So what we're talking about is the zipper and the zipper together.
It's a phenomenon of self-determination.
So first of all,
we're in the formal picture.
One of our zippers and zippers
is to be placed in one of its Z axis.
Blender is the Z axis.
Other software may be the other axis.
But it doesn't matter which axis it is.
Anyway, it must be vertical up.
Then put it in the middle position.
Then it has a pull head.
This is the place of the pull ring.
It's the place of the ground net.
And then below it is our zipper.
Adjust the position well.
Then come to the formal picture.
In the formal picture,
we can see the X axis,
which is our red line.
It happens to be the position of this pull head
with the position of the pull ruler.
So when you are modeling,
you must pay attention to this object.
It must be the place of the middle bite.
It is placed in the X axis.
Then after it is done,
there is a very important point.
That is its one point.
That is, after we select this object,
there will be a positioning ball here.
Then there will be a point here.
Then the point where the positioning ball is located
is its one point.
Then the point must be at the center point of the world coordinate.
For example, let me give an example.
Let's use this pull to make an example.
For example, I set its origin point
as the center of this object.
Then we can see that
when selecting the pull,
its positioning ball appears at its center point,
which is the point of our layer.
Then if this is the case,
it will lead to a problem in the claw,
which will lead to the position of its pull.
So here we need to move its point
to the center of its world coordinate.
So we set its origin point
to its 3D coordinate.
This is the place.
After setting it,
we can select our pull,
and pull it out together.
Sorry, we need to move it out together.
We select the file and move it out.
Then if we move it out here,
it will select an OBJ format.
Then here,
when moving it out,
select the OBJ group.
Then select the selected object.
Then let me name it.
Let me name it.
Because later,
if we move it out together,
there will be more things.
So if we name it,
let's separate it.
OK.
Slider and Puller.
This is our current file.
Then click to move it out.
Then next,
we come to our claw.
Then our type
corresponds to the selection of our pull and pull.
Then here,
select its OBJ.
Click to open.
Then here,
we can see that
it has a preview.
Then here,
we can adjust the position of this pull.
If you want to go back to the original position
after you have adjusted it,
just click on this refresh.
Then click to confirm.
It will complete this preset setting.
Then next,
let's create a pull chain.
There will be a broadcast?
There will be a broadcast.
It will be online after a week.
Our old users all know that
we will upload broadcasts
after a week.
Then this is our pull chain.
It's ready to be installed.
Then after it's installed,
we can click here
to open the puller.
Then we can see
a puller and puller
we just set up.
Then click on it,
it can make a switch.
Then this is the selection of puller and puller.
This is the puller and puller.
然后接下来呢是这一个单独的一个导出
那首先的话我们来讲一下这一个拉头的导出
那么拉头的话如果只是指导拉头的话
那它的位置其实和拉头拉边一起的位置是一样的
就是在正面的地方放在这一个Z轴的中间
中心点要对准
然后呢俯视图的时候呢
它咬合的X轴刚好就是它的一个
就是它的一个那个拉齿的位置
然后呢在测试图这边可以看到它的地面
就是刚好对准的是它挂着一个拉片的这样的一个位置
然后接下来呢再给它进行一个导出
那这边的话也是导出OBJ
OK
然后呢导出一个slider的文件
然后选择
导出OBJ
我们再来到Clue当中
然后接下来呢我们也是除了刚刚在上面用这个素材进行自定义以外
也可以在这里拉链选中拉链
点击一下这个加号也是可以进行自定义的
然后选中拉头
然后点击一下这个OBJ文件
选中slider
然后点击打开
然后打开之后呢大家可以看到在预览图当中
在预览图的当中呢也会出现这一个拉片的
这个的话是可以用来去控制这个拉片上的位置
那现在我们可以看到这个拉片的话是在这个中间咬合的地方
所以就不太正确
所以我们可以对它进行一下调节
那么这边的话就是应该用这个Z走
在Clue里面的话是Z走是朝前后向的
那我们可以把它给这个拉片呢给它拉出来
进行一下位置的调节
OK那这样的话呢我们的这个拉头呢
待会生成的时候才是一个正确的一个位置
然后点击确认
然后呢它就会创建拉链预设
然后点击确认就可以了
然后创建完之后它会默认回到我们
会用我们刚刚创建完的这一个拉头
也就是这一个拉头
那就会退出这个拉头和拉片合在一起的一个状态
那这个呢是拉头的一个创建啊
嗯我看一下大家有没有说些什么啊
显卡好贵
哎没办法呀
现在大家都在挖矿了
然后现在呢我们来讲一下哈我们的一个拉头
拉片啊
那么拉片的导出的话在这里的话呢
它这个位置因为我们刚刚说了呢它这个位置呢
它这个位置因为我们刚刚说了呢
那是拉头拉片一起倒出所以他会有点偏移啊
所以在这里边的话我们是需要对他的一个位置
因为我们刚刚说拉头拉片一起倒出所以它会有点偏移啊
进行一个挑截
好了在这里面呢我们可以来到他的一个俯视图啊
那调整一下他的位置
把这里的拉片的一个中心点啊
也是移动到我们的一个坐标轴的原点当中
然后呢维持同样的一个呃高度位置就可以了
Next, move the center point to the origin point.
So let's set the origin point on it.
After setting it, select the puller and make a guide.
Oops, my hand slipped.
After that, let it go to the OBJ guide.
Then we come to the CLO interface.
This time, we choose our puller.
Then click on the select Chinese puller file.
Then we can see this puller.
Then click to confirm.
Then it will create this preview.
After creating, it will automatically create a puller in the application.
I just saw someone ask a question.
Can I make a helmet?
This question is quite amazing.
But it can be done.
Maybe you have to think of some methods.
If you want to make a very smooth and round helmet,
then I suggest you do this in other software.
It may be more convenient.
Because our CLO is made of this plate.
And it is relatively soft.
If you want to make this kind of good standard round shape,
it may be a little difficult.
OK, then this is a guide for the puller.
After talking about the puller,
let's talk about our guide.
OK.
First of all, let's talk about the upper part.
The upper part.
There are some problems with the position.
First of all, it is in the formal picture.
The upper part is at the bottom of the floor grid.
The top of its model is parallel to the floor grid.
Then in the formal picture,
we can see that its one.
Ah.
The upper part is at the bottom of the floor grid.
And the horizontal orhabit place of this top,
it is coincidentally coincident with this coordinate.
So this point,
everybody should pay attention to.
Otherwise,
Uh, if you don't coincide,
by then the pulled out what was key,
there would be a palabras of the position of the pinching is a bit wrong.
So everybody must coincide this position.
Then this one
is the fit of the two directional.
It's that simple?
Well,
then we just
put the two of a garage lines together.
And then two of them will be pulled out together
In this case, I will divide the left and right edges into two parts
And then select two objects and pull them out together
Please pay attention, select two objects and pull them out together
Sorry, I'm sorry
My head is a little confused
It's not separated, it's separated and pulled out
It's not pulled out together, it's separated and pulled out
So let's pull this right chain first
The right side of the clothes is also the left side we see
Okay, let's select this straight button
Then let's undo it
We undo OBJ
Then here, just call it by its object name
It's not easy to mix
Then undo OBJ
Then next, let's undo the other side
Okay, in this way, we have pulled out both of them
Then next, let's come to the CLO
Then we also click on this plus number
Make a custom chain
Then select the right button
The right button is here
There is a right button and a left button
The left button has two options, open and close
Then here we choose the right button
Then after selecting the right button
Next, let's choose OBJ
Then you can see that there are two lines here
Can be used to select OBJ
Then this line above it
Corresponding to us
Is the right side of our clothes
On the top
That is, we are on the top of the top of the right pull
Below this line corresponds to
This left piece
Is the one we pull on this side
Then everyone, please pay attention to the left and right
Don't do it
Okay, then let's go to this line above
Click on this open file
Then let's select the one we correspond to
Is the one we pull on this chain
The line above corresponds to this side
Then this side of the finger
Here everyone must be careful
I can't do it
Then select these two fingers
Click on confirm
OK
Then his finger on this side
I don't know if you have noticed
There was a mysterious change here
This is a change in the shape of his finger
Then you can pull the chain down a little
OK
Then this is what we just added
Added a finger
Then the following words
Let's talk about it again
Put the rest of this next mouth
Also finished talking to everyone
Then the next mouth
First of all
Let me tell you about our
This one
The next mouth of the opening zipper
Then on this side
We just divided this one
The difference between the zipper and its lock
Then separate these two
Everyone pay attention
These two are separated
Then after separating
We also pour it out separately
Then choose him here
Then pour it out
OBJ
Give him a name
His net name is the same
Pour out
Then choose our next one
This lock
Then also pour OBJ out for him
OK
In this way
You can pour out our next mouth
Give it out
OK
Then everyone
Pay attention
When doing this next mouth
Is
He just needs the bottom part
The bottom part of our lock
Below the ground
Then
Two
In the middle of the left and right mouth
It is just in the place of the point
Just like this
One position
That's it
Including in its floating picture
You can see
It is the same bite
The place is his
A pull position
It's all similar
Then
We are done
We are also here
In our group
Also click on our
One
Add number
Then choose our mouth
Choose the next mouth
Next mouth
Choose to open
Then
The same as before
This OBJ on the top
This OBJ grass
Is used to open
Left
The
Here
One
Point
Then the grass below
Is to open the right mouth here
So everyone
Don't overdo it
OK
Then open these two OBJs
Click confirm
Then
It is the same
The next mouth
Will also change
This one we just created
Point effect
That includes
We are in this
Point
After clicking
We can see
The effect of this point
Of the shrinkage
OK
Then this is the next mouth
Then the last one
Is our
One
A closed zipper
Then this one
It's the simplest
Just an OBJ
Then
It is also
All of them
Below the grid
Then
The place where the bite is in the middle
Is the position of the X-axis
OK
Then everyone
It's just a position setting
Then
Select it
I will pour it out
Out
OK
Then after pouring
We are also
In the
Open our group
Then select our
Point
The next mouth is closed
Then
There is only one OBJ
Then let's select
Our stopper
Then we can
In the preview
See
Its effect
Click OK
Then you can complete
This prediction
Then its one
The lower mouth
There will also be a change
Then this one
Is our
A set of the zipper
Then
Summarize
Although
The previous wave of operation
Continuously pour out
Pour out
That is actually
The point
Is still
It's just
On its position
Then everyone
Can remember
The positions I just talked about
Position
The position is set
Then
The one behind you
Pour out
There is no problem
Then
This one
Is
The zipper
And its one
Stopper
Then
Let's talk about
The self-defined button
That
I don't know
Is there anyone
Find out
Maybe
Those who made the self-defined button
Will find out
Is our
In
The new version
Among
Our
Self-defined button
It looks like
It's not that simple
That is
After clicking
It will lift a window
Then
You will be able to see
A lot of things
You can like
Make a system
Explanation
So here
We
Why
Do such a feature
An update
That's mainly because
The previous
Time
Our
One
The button
It
Made
Self-defined button
Including
The button
That we have
When it
When you change
Its size
It is
The whole
Width
Or
The weight
It will have some situations, for example, when I release the button, I don't want to change it, so it will be the same size.
At this time, it may need two OBJ buttons.
Here, you can add such a function.
You can add two OBJs or three or four OBJs in the custom button.
Let's open our brand new file.
Here we can see that there is a button.
In fact, there are two OBJs, one is blue and the other is green.
These two OBJs are actually different.
One is a little bigger and the other is a little smaller.
But these two OBJs are not equal and relaxed.
For example, the large and small OBJs next to it have the same size.
Including the OBJ that is sewn back below.
It is also the same size.
If we use the function of a custom button, it will suddenly relax the whole thing.
Some people may not want such an effect.
In this case, we can do these two buttons in advance.
Make two size buttons and then make a separate guide for it.
First, select the large button.
Then also give it to the OBJ guide.
It is a large button.
It's called big.
Okay, let's get it out.
Next, let's get our small button out.
Select the small button.
Then give it to the OBJ guide.
And then here.
Sorry, I just missed a little bit.
I forgot to hook up this one.
Only select the selected item.
The reverse is better.
Please pay attention.
Be sure to hook up.
Only select the selected item.
Otherwise, it will take the whole environment.
All the things in the whole environment will be poured out.
Well, I'm sorry.
Just don't talk about it.
I'm going to record it.
Put this little button out.
OK.
Is the button facing up?
Yes, it's facing up.
OK.
Well, sorry.
I'll give you a point here.
Just now.
It's a little far.
I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
I'm a little dizzy today.
That one.
We're here.
We have two locks.
It's facing up.
Please pay attention to it.
It's the same as what we did before.
The requirements for this specific lock are exactly the same.
We're in this lock.
It's a center point.
It's going to be on our whole coordinate axis.
On a point.
On the point.
It's in our floating picture.
It's a point of contact.
And then.
When it's front.
Our whole button needs to be above the grid.
If it's like that.
Just like that.
There's a part of it below the grid.
Then it's going to have a problem.
That is.
You're going to have a set of a whole button.
This part of it will penetrate into this material.
If your button conflict is not closed.
If it's in a state, it will fight.
It's going to be unstable.
So here.
We must put the whole.
The whole OBJ.
It's all up to our ground grid.
Above.
And then.
What's next?
We're going to do it again.
A guide.
Select our big one.
This button.
And then.
Select OBJ.
Select our big one.
This OBJ.
I'm going to cover it here.
Preserved.
And then.
Hook selection.
Please guide the selected object.
And then guide OBJ.
And then.
The following.
This one.
Small size.
Lock.
And then.
Also select it.
Exit.
OBJ.
OK.
And then.
Here.
Select the small one.
This one.
OBJ.
I'm here.
Also.
Cover.
Exit.
And then.
Also.
Hook selection.
Please guide the selected object.
And then.
Exit OBJ.
After the exit.
We can.
In this folder.
You can see.
Our two OBJ.
And then.
In the class.
This one.
The lock.
Self-identity.
So.
From top to bottom.
First.
Is a shortcut.
Add.
Then.
Let's choose.
This one.
Lock.
Shutter.
And then.
On the side of the lock.
In this case.
Is your.
A whole.
A lock.
List.
And then.
Below.
Is a data input.
That.
First.
Is OBJ.
So.
Choose this.
The.
Big.
Lock.
And then.
Its.
One.
Width.
Is.
12.
In fact.
This one.
Is.
The data displayed later.
Convenient.
One of your own.
Observation.
Use.
So.
Here.
You.
Just.
According to.
Your own.
Lock.
Specifications.
Can.
Then.
Enter.
Its.
And then.
Click.
One.
Add.
Can.
A.
New.
One.
Size.
So.
In.
This.
Size.
Two.
We.
Can.
Load.
Our.
Small.
Size.
Of.
This.
Lock.
Can.
Load.
In.
Then.
Here.
Size.
A.
B.
Name.
Then.
So.
We.
This.
Lock.
Is.
Specified.
Then.
Click.
Confirm.
It.
Will.
Complete.
Lock.
Prediction.
Then.
Next.
We.
In.
Here.
We.
Can.
See.
This.
Lock.
Will.
So.
We.
Can.
See.
This.
Is.
I.
Can.
Read.
Here.
That.
I.
Can.
See.
This.
Is.
Can.
See.
That.
Is.
This.
Can.
See.
This.
Is.
When we use our button tool to add a new button, we can add the button that we just customized.
Then, just like other buttons, you can make a material setting, color, and so on.
So that's what we're talking about today.
I'm starting to drool.
Next, we're going to open everything in our file.
There's a little surprise here.
I'm going to change it back to our text surface.
First of all, the first one is the hair we talked about.
You can see Feifei's hair in the official account.
Then, shoes.
For shoes,
I'm going to import a file of a shoe that I made before.
Because someone just asked me if I could make a long-sleeve shoe.
Long-sleeve shoes can also be done.
Import it in.
Then we can also make this shoe.
And if your virtual model is changed in size, the shoes will also be changed.
To ensure that it is in a state that covers the model's legs.
Next, we can also modify this zipper.
For example, we choose the middle one.
Then we can change the zipper to the one we just made.
Then the material is made for it.
Including one of its buttons.
We can also make it.
Let's choose some of its buttons.
Then apply a default button to it.
Then we choose the default button that we just added.
Then we can also make a metal material for its material.
This way, we have applied all the materials today.
This is the content of today's live broadcast.
If you have any questions and concerns, you can ask in the comments.
I will answer them for you.
If you have any questions,
I will end my live broadcast in the next 5 minutes.
Or if you have any content that you want to know more about,
You can give me a request, maybe the next live stream will be what you want
Everyone learned something, the teacher is very happy
Let's see if there are any questions
Regarding the graphics card configuration, you can go to the official website
Let's go to the official website to check the configuration requirements
When will the next live stream be?
Probably in a month
October 15th
Can I do the same for the food?
What does your food mean?
Save the video on your mobile phone
How to change it to MP4
What is your video?
Is it a spiral video made by Chloe?
or a regular one?
If Chloe does not know the video, you can change it to MP4 for me
If you are comfortable with deep vision, you can change it to MP4 for me
If you want to save the original video as mp4 format, you can choose to save it as mp4 format.
Oh, c4d, c4d, c4d, c4d can do it, can do it, can do it, can do it, can do it, can do it, can do it, can do it, can do it, can do it.
Closed walk video, Closed walk video can be saved as mp4 format.
How to set the use of the qipao button?
Well, the qipao button, you should set that kind of plate button, right?
For the plate button, it is actually not recommended to use this kind of button.
Because this kind of button is more suitable for making a button, a button, and a button.
Then you like this one.
For the plate button, it may be better to do it in the form of a secondary button.
Only, as long as it is, as long as it is obj format, you can do the secondary button, right?
Live show, we had a live show before.
You can go back and watch the live broadcast.
Complete tutorial, from zero to zero, from zero to the end.
It's all a very detailed tutorial.
I had a live broadcast before.
Then you can watch the live broadcast.
Yes, sometimes it will be fbx.
When to use fbx?
When it comes to customizing hair and shoes.
It must be a format that requires fbx.
Then if you are a custom zipper, buckle, these words, it is obj.
How do you sew this pocket zipper?
pocket zipper
This side, in fact, I am, this is a fake pocket zipper.
He just dug a hole here.
Then, just use this zipper tool, just add it here.
Then, and then, I don't know if you are wondering if it is the seam of the two ends.
So the seam of the two ends, in fact, you can just pull this a little bit when you are modeling.
You can see that there is a gap here.
Then you can use this sewing tool directly in the 3D window.
Just sew this zipper and the panel together.
Do you have any more questions?
Billing
Why does the hair need fbx?
Uh, hair and shoes need to be in f-b-x format.
Um, we have an enthusiastic netizen, Auriout, she's already replied to you.
Because she needs a downy mesh.
大家还有什么问题吗?
如果没有的话我们今天的直播就到这里结束咯
非常感谢大家的一个关注
耳环戴不到耳朵上
但是呢如果你说你要做一个耳环的话呢
最后一个问题
这边的话就是其实耳环
我不知道你是什么样的耳环
我简单来讲一下吧
就是我随便创建一个圆吧
然后例子间就给它改小一点
其实你像这一个耳环的话
其实更多的是
你把它放在正确的位置就可以了
如果说你是想耳环跟着模特走的话
有一个想法
嗯
有一个方法你可以去参考一下
比如说
把它做成那一种就是像头发一样的格式
当然呢不适合很长的这种耳环小耳环
你就在建这个头发模型的时候
就相当于自定义头发一样
就把它放在这个耳朵的位置
那么进来的时候它也会在这个耳朵的位置
然后就可以跟着模特去进行一个走秀啊
项链怎么戴到脖子上面啊
那你做好这个文件直接在脖子上面模拟就可以了
还是说你是很复杂的一个项链呢
那如果说大家对这个耳环啊
项链这些怎么样去戴在模特身上
甚至是进行一个走秀的话
比较感兴趣的话
那可以直接就是我们后面的话
做一个专门的复建啊
可以有这样的一个需求
可以做这样一个复建的一个直播啊
教一下大家怎么样去做更多的一个配色
好的
我觉得我这边其实我本来只是想做一个环
想做一个耳环
就很简单的一个耳环
你直接放到耳朵这边就可以了
就像你正常做衣服一样
只是你这个环的话就不要模拟了
直接放过来
然后呢给它用定位球位置调好就可以了
当我这个环有点粗啊
你可以细一点的调好
我刚随便设的一个数值
像这样就是后面模拟的时候
你就把它整个冷冻主标动它就可以了
好了
那我们今天的一个直播就到这里咯
谢谢各位乡亲们的捧场
谢谢大家
那我们下期再见
拜拜
谢谢各位乡亲们的观看